{"id": "hypernymy_0_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"beach_wagon\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["genus_Galictis", "phytoplankton", "choke", "Car_body_style"], "answer_index": 3, "explanation": "Car_body_style is the hypernymy of beach_wagon; the others are very_close_matches.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "beach_wagon", "correct_answer": "Car_body_style", "synset_id": "bn:00009280n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 5, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "very_close_matches", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00009280n", "distractor_difficulty": "very_close_matches"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_1_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"warship\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["boarding", "entry", "platform", "mendelevium"], "answer_index": 2, "explanation": "platform is the hypernymy of warship; the others are semantically_related.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "warship", "correct_answer": "platform", "synset_id": "bn:00020866n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 3, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "semantically_related", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00020866n", "distractor_difficulty": "semantically_related"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_2_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"valve\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["heat_pump", "marching_band", "artificial_physical_object", "Centrospermae"], "answer_index": 2, "explanation": "artificial_physical_object is the hypernymy of valve; the others are random_unrelated.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "valve", "correct_answer": "artificial_physical_object", "synset_id": "bn:00079519n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 1, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "random_unrelated", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00079519n", "distractor_difficulty": "random_unrelated"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_3_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"Togaviridae\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["pole", "taxonomic_group", "bascule", "sled"], "answer_index": 1, "explanation": "taxonomic_group is the hypernymy of Togaviridae; the others are mixed_random_semantic.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "Togaviridae", "correct_answer": "taxonomic_group", "synset_id": "bn:00077481n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 2, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "mixed_random_semantic", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00077481n", "distractor_difficulty": "mixed_random_semantic"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_4_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"electric_locomotive\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["Conodonta", "Ursidae", "locomotive", "millipede"], "answer_index": 2, "explanation": "locomotive is the hypernymy of electric_locomotive; the others are mixed_random_semantic.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "electric_locomotive", "correct_answer": "locomotive", "synset_id": "bn:00030152n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 2, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "mixed_random_semantic", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00030152n", "distractor_difficulty": "mixed_random_semantic"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_5_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"arch\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["whitehead", "attic", "structure", "applecart"], "answer_index": 2, "explanation": "structure is the hypernymy of arch; the others are semantically_related.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "arch", "correct_answer": "structure", "synset_id": "bn:00005387n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 3, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "semantically_related", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00005387n", "distractor_difficulty": "semantically_related"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_6_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"alliance\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["constitution", "balance_wheel", "acquaintance", "toilet"], "answer_index": 0, "explanation": "constitution is the hypernymy of alliance; the others are very_close_matches.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "alliance", "correct_answer": "constitution", "synset_id": "bn:00002740n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 5, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "very_close_matches", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00002740n", "distractor_difficulty": "very_close_matches"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_7_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"fin\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["extremity", "genitive", "throat", "Heterokontophyta"], "answer_index": 0, "explanation": "extremity is the hypernymy of fin; the others are random_unrelated.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "fin", "correct_answer": "extremity", "synset_id": "bn:00034509n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 1, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "random_unrelated", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00034509n", "distractor_difficulty": "random_unrelated"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_8_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"aircraft\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["true_toad", "car_wheel", "vehicle", "ecphonesis"], "answer_index": 2, "explanation": "vehicle is the hypernymy of aircraft; the others are very_close_matches.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "aircraft", "correct_answer": "vehicle", "synset_id": "bn:00002275n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 5, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "very_close_matches", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00002275n", "distractor_difficulty": "very_close_matches"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_9_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"exhaust\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["cut", "Aegypius", "covering", "System"], "answer_index": 3, "explanation": "System is the hypernymy of exhaust; the others are random_unrelated.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "exhaust", "correct_answer": "System", "synset_id": "bn:00032215n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 1, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "random_unrelated", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00032215n", "distractor_difficulty": "random_unrelated"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_10_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"electric_motor\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["anchor", "coat", "engine", "acentric_chromosome"], "answer_index": 2, "explanation": "engine is the hypernymy of electric_motor; the others are very_close_matches.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "electric_motor", "correct_answer": "engine", "synset_id": "bn:00030156n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 5, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "very_close_matches", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00030156n", "distractor_difficulty": "very_close_matches"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_11_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"lexical_entry\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["fruit_bat", "entry", "Taylor_Monoplane", "twist-off_cap"], "answer_index": 1, "explanation": "entry is the hypernymy of lexical_entry; the others are random_unrelated.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "lexical_entry", "correct_answer": "entry", "synset_id": "bn:00026969n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 1, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "random_unrelated", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00026969n", "distractor_difficulty": "random_unrelated"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_12_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"exhaust\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["corbel_arch", "system", "Rolls-Royce_Nene", "Lyulka_TR-3"], "answer_index": 1, "explanation": "system is the hypernymy of exhaust; the others are mixed_random_semantic.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "exhaust", "correct_answer": "system", "synset_id": "bn:00032215n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 2, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "mixed_random_semantic", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00032215n", "distractor_difficulty": "mixed_random_semantic"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_13_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"alliance\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["compact", "Turbomeca_Palas", "mouthbreeder", "constitution"], "answer_index": 3, "explanation": "constitution is the hypernymy of alliance; the others are close_semantic_matches.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "alliance", "correct_answer": "constitution", "synset_id": "bn:00002740n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 4, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "close_semantic_matches", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00002740n", "distractor_difficulty": "close_semantic_matches"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_14_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"Amniota\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["Dasht-e-Kavir", "partnership", "vertebrate", "Blech"], "answer_index": 2, "explanation": "vertebrate is the hypernymy of Amniota; the others are close_semantic_matches.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "Amniota", "correct_answer": "vertebrate", "synset_id": "bn:00003574n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 4, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "close_semantic_matches", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00003574n", "distractor_difficulty": "close_semantic_matches"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_15_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"airfoil\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["dime", "Cave_hyena", "curve", "Çıpo"], "answer_index": 2, "explanation": "curve is the hypernymy of airfoil; the others are close_semantic_matches.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "airfoil", "correct_answer": "curve", "synset_id": "bn:00001682n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 4, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "close_semantic_matches", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00001682n", "distractor_difficulty": "close_semantic_matches"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_16_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"Alaudidae\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["plumb_level", "bird_family", "Buteo", "Sport_bike"], "answer_index": 1, "explanation": "bird_family is the hypernymy of Alaudidae; the others are very_close_matches.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "Alaudidae", "correct_answer": "bird_family", "synset_id": "bn:00002434n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 5, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "very_close_matches", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00002434n", "distractor_difficulty": "very_close_matches"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_17_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"foot\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["angiocarp", "amphibian_family", "algoflora", "vertebrate_foot"], "answer_index": 3, "explanation": "vertebrate_foot is the hypernymy of foot; the others are close_semantic_matches.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "foot", "correct_answer": "vertebrate_foot", "synset_id": "bn:00035679n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 4, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "close_semantic_matches", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00035679n", "distractor_difficulty": "close_semantic_matches"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_18_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"association\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["tree", "bottlecap", "person", "pectoral_fin"], "answer_index": 2, "explanation": "person is the hypernymy of association; the others are mixed_random_semantic.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "association", "correct_answer": "person", "synset_id": "bn:00006539n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 2, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "mixed_random_semantic", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00006539n", "distractor_difficulty": "mixed_random_semantic"}}
{"id": "hypernymy_19_en_to_en", "prompt": "Which of the following is a hypernym (broader category) of the English word \"head\"? (Options in English.)", "options": ["world_organization", "external_body_part", "lander", "frog"], "answer_index": 1, "explanation": "external_body_part is the hypernymy of head; the others are very_close_matches.", "metadata": {"prompt_language": "en", "word_language": "en", "options_language": "en", "root_lemma": "head", "correct_answer": "external_body_part", "synset_id": "bn:00015784n", "resource_pairing": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "difficulty_level": 5, "semantic_relation_type": "hypernymy", "language_resource_levels": {"word_language_level": "high_resource", "options_language_level": "high_resource"}, "cross_lingual_type": "intra-lingual", "prompt_type": "english_prompt", "resource_level_transfer": "high_resource_to_high_resource", "num_options": 4, "language_pair_code": "en-en", "distractor_type": "very_close_matches", "generation_timestamp": "2025-07-04T20:30:10.390379Z", "concept_name": "", "source_entry_id": "bn:00015784n", "distractor_difficulty": "very_close_matches"}}
